Inventory of the Addition to the Papers of Duke and Duke 1904-[1942-1948]-1954
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Inventory of the Addition to the Papers of Duke and Duke, 1904-[1942-1948]-1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 79-6a
This addition to the Inventory of the Papers of Duke and Duke consists of 19 boxes.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This addition to the Duke law firm papers came to the law library after the death of Helen Duke, donor of the original gift, and was given by William E. Duke, Jr. and Lucy D. Kinne.
Scope and Content Information
These additional papers to the Inventory of the Papers of Duke and Duke are primarily legal files from the Duke law firm for the years 1904-[1942-1948]-1954 and financial records of the Duke family.
Contents List
- Office Correspondence
  - Outgoing Correspondence 1841-1920, 1 folder and 4 volumes (Box 1)
  - Outgoing Correspondence 1904-1914, 3 volumes (Box 2)
  - Outgoing Correspondence 1920-1951, 3 volumes and 8 folders (Box 3)
  - Incoming Correspondence 1930-1951 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous law practice files 1920-1959, 7 folders (Box 4)
- Case Files for the 1920's and 1930's
  - Harris Accounts 1928 (Box 5)
  - Richard Philpot and Leota Ingham Diedrich Partnership Agreement 1920 (Box 5)
  - Sandridge Financial Matters 1927-1931 (Box 5)
  - B.E. Wheeler 1922-1935, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - [O'neill v. Mills] 1934 (Box 5)
  - J. Porter 1935 (Box 5)
  - Rock v. City Laundry 1932 (Box 5)
  - J.E. Simpson and Highway Department 1939 (Box 5)
  - Partial list of clients n.d. (Box 5)
- Case Files for the 1940's
  - Carroll Allen 1946 (Box 6)
  - Baxendale Will 1947 (Box 6)
  - Beck v. Beck 1945 (Box 6)
  - F. L. Berkeley, Jr. 1946 (Box 6)
  - Blackwell v. Rodgers 1946 (Box 6)
  - Blackwell v. Rodgers 1946 (Box 6)
  - Dr. E. Bodenweiser 1945 (Box 6)
  - Frank Fielden Bogg Application for Birth Certificate 1947 (Box 6)
  - Pearl Brown 1946 (Box 6)
  - Broughman v. Broughman 1946 (Box 6)
  - Eckles Burton 1946 (Box 6)
  - Della Clemons 1944-1947 (Box 6)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia v. Cary 1945 (Box 6)
  - Continental Casualty Company 1946 (Box 6)
  - Warner E. Collier 1946 (Box 6)
  - J.G. Costan Abstract 1945 (Box 6)
  - Coukos v. Moore 1945 (Box 6)
  - Mamie Curry 1946-1947 (Box 6)
  - Dameron 1945 (Box 6)
  - Dameron v. Dameron 1945 (Box 6)
  - C. G. Davis 1947 (Box 6)
  - Jerry and Annie Dowell 1946 (Box 6)
  - Duke v. Barnett 1946 (Box 6)
  - Duke v. Goodloe 1942 (Box 6)
  - Duke v. Murphy 1943-1947 (Box 7)
  - Duke v. Simpson 1946 (Box 7)
  - Early v. Curry 1947 (Box 7)
  - Eddy v. Wingfield 1946 (Box 7)
  - Edger v. Downing 1946 (Box 7)
  - Lucy Maury Fowler 1946 (Box 7)
  - Mrs. Eugene Fox 1946 (Box 7)
  - W. L. Goodwin 1945 (Box 7)
  - Goodyear Tire v. Lineweaver 1946 (Box 7)
  - Green v. Howell 1946 (Box 7)
  - Greenshaw Estate 1945 (Box 7)
  - Haga v. Robinson 1946, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Hibbert Estate 1945-1946 (Box 7)
  - Harry Johnson 1945-1946 (Box 7)
  - Johnson v. Sears, Roebuck 1947 (Box 7)
  - Jones v. Jones 1947 (Box 7)
  - Jones v. Virginia Telephone and Telegraph 1944 (Box 7)
  - Kenny v. Laird and Company 1947-1949 (Box 7)
  - Shuey P. King 1946 (Box 7)
  - Lamb v. Grbac 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - S. V. Lancaster 1946 (Box 7)
  - W. A. Law Property 1947 (Box 7)
  - Leake v. Leake 1946 (Box 7)
  - E. L. Leander 1945 (Box 8)
  - McCormick and Ellington 1946 (Box 8)
  - Maury v. Commonwealth of Virginia 1947-1948 (Box 8)
  - John G. May 1942 (Box 8)
  - Esmond Mills 1947 (Box 7)
  - Sam B. Morris 1946 (Box 8)
  - Ann C. Nicholas Estate 1946-1950, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Peregoy v. Safeway Trails 1947 (Box 8)
  - Peregoy v. "The Greek" Atlantic Lunch 1946 (Box 8)
  - Perry v. Gofney 1945 (Box 8)
  - H. P. Porter 1946 (Box 8)
  - Pure Oil Company 1946 (Box 8)
  - Quick v. Taylor Coal Company 1946 (Box 8)
  - Richey and Duke, Committee of the Mary Thonier Estate 1943 (Box 8)
  - Richey v. Evans 1948 (Box 8)
  - Saunders v. Laird and Company 1946 (Box 8)
  - Schinault v. Benson 1946 (Box 8)
  - Shifflet v. Charlottesville Lumber Company 1945 (Box 8)
  - Shifflett v. Shiflett 1945 (Box 8)
  - Shifflett v. O.P.A. 1946 (Box 8)
  - Smith v. Polis; Carpenter v. Polis 1945-1946 (Box 8)
  - Spradlin v. Robinson 1945 (Box 8)
  - Mary Thomas Appeal 1945 (Box 8)
  - Todd v. Northey's 1946 (Box 8)
  - Alice O. Towles 1949 (Box 8)
  - Josephine K. Treser 1946 (Box 8)
  - Katherine L. Ware 1941 (Box 8)
  - Thomas Washington 1946 (Box 8)
  - Mrs. Thomas A. Watson 1947 (Box 8)
  - White v. Meaks 1947-1948 (Box 8)
  - Wikman v. Home for Incurables 1945 (Box 9)
  - Willett v. Laird and Company 1946 (Box 9)
  - Ophelia Willis 1947 (Box 9)
  - Wilson v. Welch 1949-1950 (Box 9)
  - Wolfe v. Lillard 1946 (Box 9)
  - Zimmerman v. Dameron 1945-1948 (Box 9)
- Case Files for the 1950's:
  - Brookman v. Brookman 1950 (Box 9)
  - J. G. Costan Loan 1952 (Box 9)
  - Duke v. Zimmerman n.d. (Box 9)
  - Gilmer v. Brown 1953, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Susie Reeves Estate 1954 (Box 9)
  - Swift-Henderson Agreement 1952 (Box 9)
- Legal Documents:
  - Deeds 1876-1950, 13 folders (Box 10, 11)
  - Abstracts of Title n.d., 4 folders (Box 11)
- Family Business Records:
  - Kentucky Coal Companies 1889-1920, 23 folders, 12 booklets (Box 12, 13)
    Correspondence, financial records, minute books, etc.
  - [Duke family] Bond Lists and Household Accounts 1928-1929, 1931 (Box 14)
  - Helen Duke Financial Records 1931 (Box 14)
  - Mary Duke Social Service Work 1929-1939 (Box 14)
  - Mary Duke Tax Records 1928-1941 (Box 14)
  - Maymee R. Duke Financial Records 1927 (Box 14)
  - R.T.W. Duke, Jr. Estate 1926 (Box 14)
  - Certificates belonging to R.T.W. Duke, Jr. 1874, 1894, 1906 (Box 14)
  - W.E. Duke Deeds, Insurance, and Investments 1937-1947 (Box 14)
  - W.E. Duke Personal Correspondence 1948-1952, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Rosalie Slaughter Morton Financial Records 1918-1919 (Box 14)
  - Slaughter Family Financial Records 1917-1918, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Slaughter Family Ledgers 1860's and 1920's, 3 volumes (Box 15)
  - Chancellor Lot Sale 1946 (Box 15)
  - Cleremont Hotel Financial Records 1923-1927 (Box 15)
  - [Duke Property] Leases 1946 (Box 15)
  - Jefferson Hotel Bills and Receipts 1930-1932 (Box 15)
  - Development of Meadow Creek Property n.d. (Box 15)
  - Mary and Helen Duke's Malcolm Crescent Development 1952 (Box 15)
  - Specification for alteration of a house on Park Street n.d. (Box 15)
  - Sunnyside Chain of Title 1949 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Records, primarily personal 1902-1952, 14 folders, 5 volumes (Box 16, 17, 18)
- Miscellany:
  - List of securities belonging to the Miller Fund of the University of Virginia 1916 (Box 19)
  - Architectural plans for the University post office n.d. (Box 19)
  - Manuscript concerning the default of the Charlottesville National Bank 1877 (Box 19)
  - The Daily Chronicle 1864 (Box 19)
  - Liberty magazine 1939 (Box 19)
  - Newsclippings 1930's and 1940's (Box 19)
  - Memoranda and Calendar 1929-1930 (Box 19)
  - Stenographer's notepads 1930's and n.d., 17 notepads (Box 19)
  - Taylor Automobile Digest 1941 (Box 19)
  - Account Ledger 1922-1924 (Box 19)